Guide to the Clark Bruster World War I Camp Logan collection, 1917-1919 MS 554
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Clark Bruster World War I Camp Logan collection
1917-1919
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Bruster, Clark
MS 554
10 Linear Feet (7 boxes)
The collection consists of letters from Camp Logan and from France, wartime decorations, uniforms, and personal military equipment, as well as Bruster's Mother's Red Cross Uniform and service pin.
Biographical/ Historical note
Clark Bruster, a veteran of World War I, was attached to the Military Police unit, 78th Field Artillery and served at Camp Logan, Houston, Texas and overseas in France. He was a resident of Waverly, New York, home of his family.
Scope and Contents note
The collection consists of letters from Camp Logan and from France, wartime decorations, uniforms, and personal military equipment, as well as his Mother's Red Cross Uniform and service pin.
General note
Portions of this collection are available online at: https://scholarship.rice.edu/handle/1911/21893
Conditions Governing Access note
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Purchased from Charles Apfelbaum, dealer, January 2010.
Index Terms
Subjects
War; World War (1914-1918); Military
Document Types
letters (correspondence); military uniforms; memorabilia
- Series I: Correspondence, Photographs and Memorabilia, 97634
  - Correspondence to Mr. and Mrs. H.C. Bruster; 1917, n.d., 97636 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bruster, Clark; Correspondence from Fort Slocum, NY and on route to Fort Riley, KS, July 1917, 97637 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bruster, Clark; Correspondence from Camp Logan, TX, Nov. – Dec. 1917, 97638 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bruster, Clark; Correspondence from Camp Logan, TX, Jan. – Feb. 1918, 97639 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bruster, Clark; Correspondence from Camp Logan, TX, Marc h – April 1918, 97640 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bruster, Clark; Correspondence from Camp Doniphan, Fort Sill, OK, May 1918, 97641 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bruster, Clark; Correspondence on route to and from Camp Mills, Long Island, NY, July 1918, 97642 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bruster, Clark; Correspondence on route to France and from locations in France, July-Aug. 1918, 97643 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bruster, Clark; Correspondence from various locations in France, Sept. – Oct. 1918, 97644 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bruster, Clark; Correspondence from various locations in France, Nov. 1918 – Feb. 1919, 97645 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bruster, Clark; Correspondence from Chamonix, France, Feb. – March 1919, 97646 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bruster, Clark; Correspondence from Aix les Bains, St. Jervais, and Marseilles, France, April – May 1919, 97647 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence from Campbell Hall, n.d., 97648 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Envelopes of letters mailed to Bruster family, Waverly, NY, 1917-1918 (Folder 1 of 2), 97649 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Envelopes of letters mailed to Bruster family, Waverly, NY, 1917-1918 (Folder 2 of 2), 97650 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Photographs, 97651 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - French hotel tickets, 97652 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Individual pay record book of Clark Bruster, 1919, 97653 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - French tax exemption coupon booklet, 97654 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Postcards of Chamonix and Aix les Bains, France (correspondence side blank), 97655 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - WWI Victory medal with "France" clasp, New York State WWI service medal and US Treasury Dept. Victory Liberty Loan disk, 97662 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Service medallion of Waverly, NY and Certificate of Appreciation presented to Clark Bruster, 97663 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Honor Roll – "Soldiers, Sailors and Nurses from Sayre, PA", 97658 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - The Evening Times newspaper; Sayre, PA, Sept. 13, 1919, 97659 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Programs, 97664 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - American flag (13" x 22.5"), 97665 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Pennant – One blue star on white field, 97666 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Series II: Uniforms, 97635
  - Red Cross Uniform, 97667; Dress uniform, blue Veil, blue Cap, blue with white band and Red Cross emblem Red Cross service medal Red Cross cotton bag (Box 3)
  - US Army Uniform, 97668; Military Police (MP) armband Dog tags Campaign Ribbons Collar devices: "US 78" and Artillery "A" Bronze victory lapel button World War Service medal - presented by the citizens of Tioga County, NY (Box 4)
  - Metal helmet and leather legging, 97669 (Box 5)
  - Army dress cap, 97670 (Box 6)
  - Cap, informal; metal mess kit; shaving brush; 1 pair of puttees; cloth kit with embroidered letter "B"; Masonic apron presented by Waverly Lodge No. 407, 97671 (Box 7)